We did add a toolbar in the last lecture,
Bir ara ubuu ve The Last Lecture yaptk.
let's now add a logo and I'm not going to add the logo to navigation,
imdi bir logo ekleyelim ve logoyu navigasyona eklemeyeceim.
I'm going to add it to components because theoretically, we could use that logo anywhere in the application.
Teorik olarak o logoyu uygulamann herhangi bir yerinde kullanabileceimiz iin iki bileen ekleyeceim.
So I'm going to create a new folder there, logo, and in that folder a new file, logo.js.
Bu yzden orada yeni bir klasr oluturacam ve bu klasrde J S. yeni bir dosya logosu.
Now I actually want to use an image file as a logo so I'm going to store that image file in the assets
imdi aslnda bir grnt dosyas olarak bir logo kullanmak istiyorum, o resim dosyasn ve orijinalinin orada
folder, to be precise there
olmas iin klasr depolayacam.
I'll also create the images subfolder into which this image should go.
Ayrca, bu resmin iine gidecek olan resim alt klasr oluturacam.
Now you can find that image I'm talking about attached to this video,
imdi, bahsettiim grnty bu videoyla balantl olarak bulabilirsiniz.
simply add it to the images folder then and you should get this burger logo here, a burger with a transparent
Daha sonra grnt klasrne ekleyin ve bu burger logosunu burada effaf bir arka plana sahip
background.
bir burger almalsnz.
Now I want to use that logo in the logo.js file and the logo component is just going to be a functional
imdi bu logoyu kullandnzda herhangi bir logo J S dosyas ve logo bileeni sadece ilevsel bir
component,
bileen olacak.
so as always,
Her zamanki gibi.
component which looks like this which imports react and which then of course exports this function as the
Bu ekilde grnen, ithal eden tepki veren ve elbette bu ilevi varsaylan olarak
default.
ihra eden Cupola.
And now, I simply want to display that image here,
Ve imdi sadece o grnty burada grmek istiyorum.
I also want to wrap it in a div which sets the background for the image though because the image itself
Ayn zamanda grntnn arka plann belirleyen bir div iine kaydrmak istiyorum nk grnt kendisinin effaf bir
has a transparent background and I want to set a white one here.
arka plan var ve burada beyaz bir tane oluturmak istiyorum.
And of course we could even go so far to accept the background color via props and change it dynamically
Ve elbette, neden sahne alyor ve dinamik olarak deien arka plan rengini kabul edebilmek iin imdiye kadar gidebiliyoruz.
but that's not what I'm going to do here.
Ama burada yapacam ey bu deil.
So we have just wrapping div in there,
Yani sadece orada divine sarglyoruz.
we're going to have the image tag.
Resim etiketi alacaz.
Now the image tag will have a source property and this should actually be set dynamically. Now you could
resim etiketi bir kaynak zelliine sahip olacak ve bu, yalnzca Varlklar klasrne gidip daha
think that you simply say go up to the assets folder and then to the images folder and to burger logo
sonra grnt klasrne ve Bergere logosu PNC'sine gitmenizi syleyebileceinizi dndnz gibi aslnda dinamik olarak ayarlanmaldr.
png.
imdi
Now this will not work as you would expect it to work due to the way our build workflow here is set
imdi, i yerinde i akmzn kurulma ekli nedeniyle bunun almasn beklediiniz gibi
up,
almyor.
keep in mind, the source folder is only the folder we're working in. In the end, webpack will take all these
Kaynak klasrn yalnzca Hindistan'da almakta olduumuz klasr olduunu ve Westpac'n tm bu dosyalar
files, bundle them together and create a new output folder.
birlikte paketleyip yeni bir kt klasr oluturacan unutmayn.
We can see that here because we're in development mode where all of that will happen in memory
O yla bakabiliriz, nk gelime modundayken hepsinin belleinde gerekleecei anlamna gelir.
but once we do publish our app, we will get a real different folder where all the optimized, compiled
yaynladmzda optimize edilmi derlenmi ve paketlenmi varlklarn bulunduu farkl bir klasr alacaz, bu
and bundled assets are contained in. Now therefore these assets folder here to the source folder will
nedenle burada kaynak klasre ait bu varlklar klasr herhangi bir gerek sunucuya gnderilmeyecektir.
not be shipped to any real server,
Ancak, bir keresinde uygulamamz
the whole source folder won't be shipped there.
Btn kaynak klasr orada gnderilecek.
Hence we should also make webpack aware of the fact that we're using this image and we're actually doing
Bu nedenle WePay' da bu grnty kullandmz bilmeliyiz ve
that by importing the image into our javascript file.
aslnda bunu javascript dosyamza ie aktararak yapyoruz.
Now of course just like for the css files,
imdi tabii ki sadece grnd gibi u ekildedir.
this does not mean that webpack mixes the image with our javascript code,
Bu, WePay'n grnty Javascript koduyla kartrd anlamna gelmez.
how would that look like
Bu nasl olur da.
anyways? It just means we make webpack aware of the fact that we're using this image and webpack will then
ileyeceini fark ettik ve bu da resmi kendi yapacak grnts ileyecektir; oluturduu hedef dizinine aktarr.
handle this image with a special plug-in or a special module that was added to webpack, to its config,
Her neyse, WePay'n bu grnty kullandmz ve web sayfasn daha sonra bu
will handle the image, will basically copy it over to the destination directory it creates,
grnty zel bir fi ile veya web'e eklenecek zel bir modlle
again only in memory during development and we'll even optimize the image.
Yine sadece gelime srasnda hafzada ve biz bile grnty optimize ettik.
So here we can simply import burger logo from
Dolaysyla, buradan Bergere logosunu ie aktarabiliriz.
and now the path to the image,
Ve imdi POV grntye.
so in assets images, add the file. And burger logo here will in the end just receive the path off the image
SS grntlerinde dosyay ekleyin ve Bergere logosunu buradan aln ve yine de WePay'n kopyalayaca
where webpack will copy it to.
grntnn yolunu alacaksnz.
So this will be dynamically resolved,
Dolaysyla bu dinamik olarak zlecek.
so here we can simply set source to burger logo and this will again refer to a string in the end to
Dolaysyla, kayna Bergere logosuna basite ayarlayabiliriz ve bu, yine iyi depolanan DB depolam DB
the path where webpack stored the optimized and copied image.
optimize edilmi ve kopyalanan grntnn POV'un sonundaki bir dizeye atfta bulunacaktr.
This is important to understand,
Anlamak nemlidir.
now also set an alt text where I'll simply will write my burger or whatever your brand name should be.
imdi tm metin kelimelerinin hepsi benim burgerim veya markanzn ad ne olursa olsun yazacaktr.
So this is the image,
Bu D-Mich da yle. imdi biz de arka plan rengimiz var emin olun ve bunun iin orada bir sonbahar siestas bir logo ekleyeceiz emin olalm.
let's now make sure that we also have a background-color and for that, I'll add a logo css file. There
Bir logo yaratacam Seer'n, beyaz bir arka plan rengi oluturmak istediim snf olarak belki
I'll create a logo css class where I want to set a background-color of white, maybe set up padding
bellein evresindeki div kenarlarna kadar uzatlmamas iin grntnn etrafna 8 piksel
of let's say 8px around the image so that it doesn't stretch to the edges of that surrounding div
doldum diyelim doldurma ayarn yapmak istiyorum ve bu olmas gerekiyor .
and that should be it
Sanrm% 100'lk fark yksek ve imdi de nemli.
I guess. Make the div of height 100% and now important,
Ayrca sonunda bu logo snfn alacak olan babas Dave'in iindeki resmi ekillendirin.
let's also style the image inside that div which will receive that logo class here in the end
Ve grnt yksekliini bu yzde ykseklie gtrmek iin grnt
and let's set the image height to 100% too, so that the image does take this height at a maximum
yksekliini yzde 100 olarak ayarlayalm ve daha yksek olaca varsaylan varsaylan yksekliini almaz.
and it does not take its default inherent height which would be higher.
imdi bu dosyay kaydedin ve tabii ki
Now save that file and of course import it, import to classes from the logo file in your logo.js file
logo js dosyasndaki logo dosyasndan snflara aktarn ve snf adnz Colossus logosunu evreleyen div'e atayn.
and then assign your class name classes.Logo to the surrounding div.
imdi bunu kullanalm ve stilin ihtiyalarmza uyup uymadn grelim.
Let's now use this and see if the styling fits our needs,
Ara ubuu bileenine gidiyorum nk buray burada kullanmak istiyorum.
I'll go to the toolbar component because that is where I want to use it here
Ve elbette imdi kk bir ithalat logosu ekleyeceim.
and of course I'll now add it. So I'll import logo
u andan itibaren, st bileenin
from and now we have to navigate up all the way to the top components folder and then import that logo
klasrne kadar ilerleyip logoyu js dosyasndan ie aktarmak zorundayz.
from the logo.js file
Ve burada logomuzun bileenini ie aktarabilir ve X kovalamacna ekleyebilirim. Hereyi kurtar ve bu iyi grnyor.
and here, I can then simply import my logo component and add it to jsx.
Sanrm imajmn bu kadarn harcamak istemiyorum.
Save everything and this looks ok,
Belki de etrafnda kahverengi bir alan olmal, bylece basite logodaki ara ubuundayz.
I guess I don't want my image to span the full height of this,
Afedersiniz ki, logo'nun yalnzca geniliin yzde 80'ini kullandndan emin olmak iin kod olarak diyor gryorum.
maybe there should be some brown space around it. So what we can simply do is in the toolbar, in the logo
bunu daha sonra tekrar dokunacamz syleyebilirim.
excuse me, adjust the css code to make sure that the logo only uses 80% of the width.
Zaten yan ekmeceye uygulamaya baladmzda
I can already say we will have to touch this later on again when we start implementing this in the side
Ancak ara ubuu iin bunu yapmalsnz.
drawer
Ayrca, kutu boyutunu sipari kutusuna ayarlayalm, bylece yzde 80'lik ykseklikte dolguyu da iereceksiniz.
but for the toolbar, this should actually do it.
Ve son olarak belki de kenarlar yuvarlatlm olacak ekilde be piksellik bir kenarlk yarap verelim.
Let's also set the box-sizing to border box so that the 80% height also includes the padding,
imdi bu kaydedersek, bence gerekten gzel grnen bu logoyu alrsak.
and finally maybe let's also give does a border radius of 5px to have rounded edges.
Tabii ki bunu her zaman ihtiyalarnza gre tweetebilirsin.
Now with that if we save this, we get this logo which looks really nice in my opinion,
Bundan sonra navigasyon eleri zerinde almaya balayalm.